

# **AISTĖ SIMOKAITIENĖ**

KAUNAS, LITHUANIA · +370 605 44277 AUSTRAITE@GMAIL.COM

LinkedIn · GitHub



Programming
Python, HTML, C/C++

Data analysis

Creation of new products

Quality management systems

Auditing

Technical documentation

Intellectual property management

3D printing

3D modelling

3D reconstruction



**LANGUAGES** 

Lithuanian English German



#### HOBBIES

I love travelling, 3D printing (running 4 FDM and SLA printers at home), photography, Arduino programming and learning new stuff.



Passionate, results-driven R&D engineer, leader with can-do attitude with more than 6 years biomedical engineering experience at UAB Ortho Baltic. I helped Ortho Baltic R&D team to create personalized implantable medical devices manufacturing facility, to equip and validate quality control laboratory from zero. I also helped to introduce 4 personalized implants solutions to the market and claim 4 patents.

All the time I been working with many types of data and been curious how to improve some data processing steps, make them faster, more reliable and fail proof.

When I started working on AI/ML based project, I dived deeper into Python, data science and started intensively learning related principles.

Currently I'm looking for a position where I would be challenged enough to keep learning and could bring some values from highly regulated medical device industry.



## **EXPERIENCE**

### **UAB ORTHO BALTIC**

PATENT ENGINEER

06 2020 - 08 2020

- Helping inventors and R&D teams with every aspect of the intellectual property processes;
- Conducting searches for prior art, FTO analysis;
- Drafting patent applications, preparing responses to reports from patent examiners, communicating with patent attorneys;
- Ensuring application and renewal deadlines are met.
- Creating and implementing IPR procedures;
- Conducting internal trainings and demonstrations to facilitate incorporation of ideas brought forward by team members and to keep them informed about IPR;
- Product prototyping, technical documentation;
- Preparing project applications, plans, reports and deliverables for EU and national projects.

#### **R&D ENGINEER / 3D RECONSTRUCTION ENGINEER**

01 2015 - 05 2020

- Product prototyping, market analysis, creation and validation of new quality control and manufacturing procedures, communication with clinicians and other stakeholders;
- Leading internal audits for ISO 13485, ISO 9001, ISO 14001 and ISO 27001 standards;
- Preparing and maintaining technical documentation of class IIa-III medical devices;
- Managing company's intellectual property;
- Project applications, plans, reports and deliverables for EU and national projects.

### **R&D TECHNICIAN / LABORATORY ASSISTANT**

01 2014 - 12 2014

- Product prototyping, technical documentation;
- Project applications, plans, reports and deliverables for EU and national projects;
- And other activities relating R&D, Radiation Safety, QMS and Quality control.

INTERN MEDICAL PHYSICIST NATIONAL CANCER INSTITUTE	02 2013 – 06 2013
HEAD OF THE SECRETARIAT UNIT LITHUANIAN SCOUTING  • Awarded Honor for Services	03 2012 – 04 2013
EDUCATION	
IBM/Coursera · APPLIED DATA SCIENCE SPECIALIZATION Vilnius Codding School · PYTHON PROGRAMMING LSMU · MASTER · BIOMEDICAL SCIENCES KTU · BACHELOR · APPLIED PHYSICS	01 2020 - 05 2020 03 2020 - 05 2020 09 2015 - 06 2017 09 2009 - 06 2013